An emotion picture.
Dirty Computer is a music, drama, romance film directed by Emma Westenberg.
The story of a young woman named Jane 57821, who is living in a totalitarian near-future society where citizens are referred to as 'computers.' 'Dirty Computer' explores
humanity and what truly happens to life, liberty and the pursuit of happiness when mind and machines merge, and when the government chooses fear over freedom.
Jane 57821, played by Janelle Monáe.
Zen, played by Tessa Thompson.
Ché, played by Jayson Aaron.
Virgin Victoria, played by Michele Hart.
Cleaner #1, played by Dyson Posey.
Scream Police, played by Alex Wexo.
Dirty Computer is a 2018 dystopian musical science fiction film.
It serves as a visual companion to Dirty Computer, the
third studio album by Janelle Monáe.
Billed as an "emotion picture", Dirty Computer tells the story of android Jane 57821 and her struggles as she "attempts to break
free from the constraints of a totalitarian society that forcibly makes [her] comply with its homophobic beliefs".
The film was produced by Wondaland, Monáe's multimedia production company, and was directed by Andrew Donoho and Chuck Lightning, with the music video portions of the film
directed by Donoho ("Django Jane"), Lacey Duke ("I Like That"), Alan Ferguson ("Crazy, Classic, Life", "Make Me Feel"), and Emma Westenberg ("Pynk", "Screwed").
The film explores themes of rebellion, mind
control, dystopia, satire, music video.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.